<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-06T21:00:22-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sebastian Yang</title><subtitle>This is the personal website for Sebastian Yang aka 杨毓恺.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Artlas Mobile AR App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artlas Mobile AR App" /><published>2021-05-20T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-20T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas">&lt;p&gt;Point your camera to a building, and Artlas will put its name in front of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time when you want to find the name of a building, no need to circle all the way to the front to read its name or zoom in and out on your Maps app. Just point and click with Artlas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is currently available only in parts of certain cities. When the time is right, head out and see if it works in your area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is developed by Sebastian Yang for fun.
Built with Swift, ARKit, RealityKit, MapKit, UIKit, and CoreLocation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/artlas-ar-building-names/id1567798806&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/artlas-ar-building-names/id1567798806&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Artlas/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first AR app. I learned a lot of cool technical stuff using ARkit, but here are some of my main takeaways that might be helpful to anyone developing AR apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-user-guidance-and-showing-actionable-steps-in-ar-are-critical&quot;&gt;1. User Guidance and Showing Actionable Steps in AR are Critical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most apps only need to guide the user once at the beginning and most actionable steps are implicit and self-explanatory: you see the Wifi bar goes down, you will move closer to the WIFI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not in AR. In AR, we have to constantly guide and inform the user about the current state of the app such as tracking availability, accuracy, and actionable steps to improve it. In AR Geotracking, we also need to tell the user why the app fail to localize the user and how to solve it (trees blocking the view? Move too fast? No buildings in view? etc). A case in point is, in Artlas, if the user looks down, the app will explicitly prompt the user to look up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guidances are critical to ensure a smooth user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-universal-icons-in-ar-is-an-area-for-exploration&quot;&gt;2. Universal Icons in AR is an Area for Exploration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, hopefully, there will be universal icons in AR, similar to the WiFi and battery icons, that represent different states and implicitly tells the user what to do, especially for common information like the tracking accuracy and actions like move the camera to scan the environment. If so, we won’t have to put an overlay text over the camera view every time we want to guide the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-be-thorough-in-reasons-for-using-sensitive-information&quot;&gt;3. Be Thorough in Reasons for Using Sensitive Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of Artlas was actually rejected because when explaining the reasons for using the user location, I only mentioned I use it for finding nearby buildings but forgot to mention it is also being used for ARkit’s Geotracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, being explicit and thorough in reasons for using sensitive information, is beneficial for both the user’s understanding and the developer’s shipping schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;under-the-hood&quot;&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artlas uses Apple ARKit’s Geotracking feature. It uses your GPS coordinates and the image stream captured from your camera to understand where you are in the real world. Then it searches for nearby places of interest using MapKit and finds the nearest one in the direction you are pointing towards when you hit the button. Then it will generate a 3D text object using RealityKit and place it at the location of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We value privacy so we do not store any user information. Everything is done locally using Apple’s native APIs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><category term="AR_VR" /><summary type="html">Point your camera to a building, and Artlas will put its name in front of it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FitSaber VR Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FitSaber VR Research" /><published>2021-05-19T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-19T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber">&lt;p&gt;Promoting Cognitive Engagement and Physical Activity in Virtual Reality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology use grows at an exponential rate and sedentary behavior increases in the wake of the global pandemic, evidence-based practices promoting both physical activity and cognitive engagement are needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is the development of the research-based “making” portion of an experimental study to examine the effects on cognitive skills in 18- to 23- year-olds from varying virtual reality (VR) conditions. This study uses a between-subject design with participants recruited through the university Psychology Subject Pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conditions are experimentally modified VR rhythm games. Participants are presented a stream of approaching directional blocks and respond by moving their arms left, right, up, down, or diagonal depending on the direction of an arrow on the target block using a corresponding saber. There will be meticulous manipulations to the amount of physical activity and cognitive demands for each condition. Participants will be randomly assigned to one of four conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise (Standard) Condition: high physical activity + low cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combined (Standard + Rule Switch) Condition: high physical activity + high cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cognitive (Sedentary + Rule Switch) Condition: low physical activity + high cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;or Control (Sedentary Standard) Condition: low physical activity + low cognitive demands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants in all conditions train for 45 minutes total (9 songs total) with 15 minutes of practice beforehand. Participants’ cognitive skills will be assessed at pretest and posttest before and after training using standard neurocognitive measures and questionnaires. This project shows the development of the conditions, game features, and outcome measures utilized to assess cognitive skills in young adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official testing will start in the fall of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is sponsored by Facebook Reality Lab and CMU SURG Grant for VR equipment. Facebook and SURG did not participate in the design and implementation of the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hTGAXOeDxpU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I had the honor to be the VR Team Lead coordinating the development of the VR software that we used for research. Here are some of my takeaways from this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-be-comfortable-with-ambiguity&quot;&gt;1. Be Comfortable with Ambiguity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology research in VR is an emerging field. There weren’t a lot of precedents we can refer to. Hence, we spent an entire semester pilot testing. We tried many different conditions using the original Beat Saber game and our paper prototypes to narrow down to the aforementioned four conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When conducting research, feeling comfortable embracing ambiguity and uncertainty is an essential skill, especially in the field of VR, where few researchers have ever set foot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-visualize-the-work-in-progress&quot;&gt;2. Visualize the Work In Progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanban board is a great tool to visualize the work in progress. Unlike a production line, where the bottleneck can be identified easily by seeing stuff piling up, a software engineering team’s work in progress is not visible. However, it is critical for the leader in the team to understand the current state of the project and where the bottleneck is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, by using Kanban to show the work in progress and deadlines, I had a complete understanding of where we were and where we were going. We were able to build and ship the game with all the core functionalities within one semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-use-spatial-audio-to-make-vr-immersive&quot;&gt;3. Use Spatial Audio to Make VR Immersive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having every sound coming from an actual source is one of the keys to an immersive experience in VR. In our FitSaber, the satisfying slicing sound will come from the location where the block is sliced. VR has the ability to make the players completely believe in the world they are in, and the lack of positional audio will ruin the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;under-the-hood&quot;&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we re-created a commercially available virtual reality game called Beat Saber. We did it in Unity from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our recreation, it not only read the beat maps from normal beat saber game but also includes many features like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tutorials for new players,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;practice trails to get players familiar with the game,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Auditory and visual feedback to reinforce the player’s behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple songs for participants to play&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And a scoring system to let the participants know how they are doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we developed a GUI that is only visible to the researcher and not visible to the participants in VR. The researcher can use the UI to manipulate the slice direction for our research study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game also will automatically save data about the player’s accuracy. This is much more efficient and less error-prone than manually enter data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use C# to create this game, GitHub for version control, and we deployed an agile method to conduct weekly sprints. And use kanban to track our progress across each sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers: Kalpa Anjur, Adrian Mester, Sebastian Yang, Matthew Komar, Adrian Ma, George Whitfield Jr, Suanna Moron&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentors: Cassondra Eng, Dr. Anna Fisher, Dr. Erik Thiessen&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="AR_VR" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><summary type="html">Promoting Cognitive Engagement and Physical Activity in Virtual Reality</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PNC Card-Linked Offers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PNC" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PNC Card-Linked Offers" /><published>2021-05-18T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-18T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PNC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PNC">&lt;p&gt;In this project, we work with Numo, a fintech subsidiary of the PNC bank, to analyze data of PNC customers to improve the redemption rate of card-linked offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Card Linked Offers (CLOs) are a version of digital coupons that are shown to the customer whenever they open the PNC mobile app. Once the user “activates” the offer, it becomes linked to their credit/debit card. Then, when they purchase at the brand using the linked card, the discount is seamlessly applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have access to a huge amount of anonymized data. There are more than 300 million anonymized accounts in our dataset. We have access to the everyday transaction, offer served, offer activation, and offer redemption data of each account on any given day from 2017 to 2020. Not to mention the data about offers, such as merchant name, discount amount, and duration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we were able to improve the recommendation accuracy by 12% to achieve a total average accuracy of 77%. We define accuracy as the percentage of users that redeemed our recommendation in the test period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was the de facto leader in this project. It gave me a rare opportunity to work with massive real-world data. Here are some of my main takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-think-declaratively-in-sql&quot;&gt;1. Think Declaratively in SQL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dataset with over 300 million users is not something easy to query. Hence, it is critical to think declaratively and not programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our early code, we saved a list of customers and loop through the list doing a SQL call for each user. That’s clear programmatical thinking. It took us 14 minutes to get information about 100 users. Later I improved the code by doing a single SQL call with a lot of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;where&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;join&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;having&lt;/code&gt;. I was able to get 200K users’ info in the same time frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-divide-and-conquer&quot;&gt;2. Divide and Conquer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tool that applies in almost all disciplines and scenarios is breaking a big problem into multiple smaller ones in a mutually exclusive and collectively exhaustive way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we were initially befuddled by the huge and messy dataset that contained 11 tables. When conducting EDA, we were not sure where to start. Hence, I break all EDA into three subcategories: user information, offer information, and user-offer interaction. This really helped the team move forwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same idea was also applied in the recommendation step. We broke the task into three steps: segment the customer, recommend merchant, then recommend offers within a merchant. This makes big problems more approachable, and the team gains more confidence every time a smaller problem is tackled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-normalized-the-tables&quot;&gt;3. Normalized the Tables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One major obstacle is that the database is not normalized. The data is formatted by weekly and monthly snapshots. This led to a lot of duplicates in the data with no clear way to uniquely identify each row.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most datasets we work with at school are often BCNF or 3NF. But in the real world, many datasets are not even in 1NF. In the future, I will always normalize the database if possible so that the data scientists can have an easier time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;under-the-hood&quot;&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To tackle the problem, we set up a three-step approach. First, we conducted an exploratory data analysis (EDA) to understand the huge dataset we were given. Then, we conducted a customer segmentation by their spending behavior with an unsupervised machine learning algorithm. In doing so, we separate the customers into different spending habit groups (e.g. stay at home parent vs traveling salesperson). Lastly, we build a recommendation engine for each customer group. We noticed many users tend to redeem the same offer multiple times, so the engine is made of two parts: a memorizer with decaying memory and a recommender for the new offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For segmentation, we used the k-means algorithm in a 30-dimensional feature space, each dimension represents a customer’s spending behavior in an industry. We used 20 thousand users’ spending behavior in two months as a training set&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For recommendation, we used an item-to-item similarity collaborative filter. Essentially, it calculated the cosine similarity between offers based on redemption data alone. e.g. if customers A and B both redeemed at Shop 1 and Shop 2. Then our algorithm will think Shop 1 and 2 are similar since they are been patronized by the same group of people. In the future, if a customer C redeemed at Shop 1, our engine will recommend Shop 2 to C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sampled 20 thousand users who redeemed in June, July, and August. We use June and July data as training sets and August data as a test set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers: Sebastian Yang, Elena Chen, Lijing Yao, Elena Gong, Carl Yang&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentors: Rebecca Nugent, Peter Freeman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carnegie Mellon Statistics &amp;amp; Data Science Department&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Data_Analysis" /><summary type="html">In this project, we work with Numo, a fintech subsidiary of the PNC bank, to analyze data of PNC customers to improve the redemption rate of card-linked offers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Consulting for PAFA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PAFamily" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consulting for PAFA" /><published>2021-05-17T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-17T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PAFamily</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/PAFamily">&lt;p&gt;In this project, we are helping PA Parent and Family Alliance to improve the information architecture of their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Family Alliance is a federally funded non-profit organization that provides support for parents whose children are experiencing social, emotional, behavioral, or mental health challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon evaluating their website analytics, we identified a major retention problem. Hence, we identified two goals: retaining new users coming to the website for the first time and retaining existing users through the value of the membership experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address these goals, we set out to redesign key parts of the Family Alliance’s website, as well as streamlining the new user onboarding process, and improving returning user’s membership experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To evaluate our progress, we conducted two rounds of user testing on a total of 18 users, asking them to complete five critical tasks before and after the redesign. The result showed our redesign reduced the proportion of users that failed to find resources on the website from 66% to 0% and reduced the average time spent on doing these tasks taken by 68.2% and as much as two minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-dont-treat-the-symptoms-find-the-root-cause&quot;&gt;1. Don’t Treat the Symptoms, Find the Root Cause&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the client came to us, they were using 30 different apps to maintain their business and experiencing engagement issues with their members. They wanted us to “streamline the business process” by finding cheaper integrated alternatives and develop a new membership webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, these were only the symptoms. We made a business flow chart and identified the root cause was the information architecture of the website: 1) Because the website is not organized, our client felt free to add more functionalities to the website, causing an overblown tech stack and the need to streamline. 2) Because the website is not organized, the users didn’t know how to navigate and find useful information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our client would not have been in a better place if we simply follow their requests. Because we will only be treating the symptoms and not the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-take-ownership-and-make-data-driven-decision&quot;&gt;2. Take Ownership and Make Data-Driven Decision&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very easy to turn a technical consulting job into an outsourcing job. Simply do what the client told you to do, and both the client and you will be happy but the root cause is still there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I thought of myself as a product manager for the Family Alliance with the goal of improving the user experience and the usability of the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used both qualitative data from user testing and quantitative data such as heatmap to inform the redesign of the website. Base on web traffic data, I was also able to propose a non-technical solution using Slack for membership engagement instead of a membership page. The client was thrilled to see our final deliverables and even offered us to work with them over the summer. None of these would be possible had I not taken ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-dont-rush-the-process-build-trust-gradually&quot;&gt;3. Don’t Rush the Process: Build Trust Gradually&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we identified the root cause, I came up with a wireframe that completely reorganized the entire website. It reduced the 7 tabs in the navigation bar to just 3 by consolidating and redesigning some pages. Even though all our teammates thought this was the right approach, our client was not thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think this was mostly because we hadn’t build up trust with the client yet. They were understandably skeptical of the big changes we proposed, especially on a website that they’ve invested so much time and energy on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, we switched courses and started to work on smaller fixes and improvements first (even though we knew some fixes will be obsolete once we implement the redesign). This really helped us build trust. We gradually move to redesign a single page, and then multiple pages. In the last two weeks, we finally redesigned the landing page and the navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, when working in client-facing roles, it’s important to understand the client’s reluctance and gradually build trust to overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student Consulting Team:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Yang served as the project manager. He is a third-year student majoring in Information Systems with a dual degree in Statistics &amp;amp; Machine Learning. He will be interning as a project manager at Blizzard over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Monroe acted as the client relationship manager. He is a senior majoring in Information Systems with an additional major in Philosophy. He will be starting in a full-time software engineering role at the end of the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Cheung served as technical lead. He is a senior majoring in Information Systems and interned at Microsoft over the previous summer. He will be starting in a full-time position as a software developer in August.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><summary type="html">In this project, we are helping PA Parent and Family Alliance to improve the information architecture of their website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AnySync iOS App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AnySync iOS App" /><published>2021-03-12T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-12T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to do something with friends, but feared that your friends may turn you down? Even if your friends said yes, have you ever worried that they might have been pressured to say yes? This situation can happen when inviting friends to play video games or even in a couples’ sex life. Our app achieves true consent where both parties spontaneously say yes, but at different times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create an activity and share it with your friends&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tap ”Sync” if you are in the mood&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If ONLY you tap, your friends would never know&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if your friends are also in the mood, they will also tap “Sync” on their phones&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then both of you will be notified!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using our app, one party won’t feel discouraged if another party refuses. Because if one taps the “Sync” button, the other party won’t know it unless the other party also taps the button within the specified time-frame. You can even create as many syncs as you like for different purposes: “Friday Happy Hours”, ”Sex”, “Eat out tonight”, etc!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/anysync/id1556964175&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/anysync/id1556964175&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/anysync/appstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-notes&quot;&gt;Developers Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built with Swift, Google Firebase, and ReactJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed in CMU TartanHack 2021 under 40 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App Developed by Karl Xiao, Kevin Wang, and Sebastian Yang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><summary type="html">Have you ever wanted to do something with friends, but feared that your friends may turn you down? Even if your friends said yes, have you ever worried that they might have been pressured to say yes? This situation can happen when inviting friends to play video games or even in a couples’ sex life. Our app achieves true consent where both parties spontaneously say yes, but at different times.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Legend of the White Snake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Legend of the White Snake" /><published>2020-12-20T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake">&lt;p&gt;This is a retell of the Chinese traditional folklore &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legend_of_the_White_Snake&quot;&gt;The Legend of the White Snake&lt;/a&gt;. The game is developed for Tencent Institute of Games and is available for download at &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/%E7%99%BD%E8%9B%87-%E7%BA%B8%E4%BC%9E/id1535362205&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt; or by searching “白蛇·纸伞”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most challenging and exciting project I’ve worked on. I was the Product Manager/Programmer of the game and worked with 8 people across three different timezones to develop this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led the team to go through 12 sprints in 3 months. We achieved weekly builds, hit 3 release milestones and conducted 5 rounds of user testings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/whitesnake/level1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/whitesnake/level1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Level 1&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, we did detailed documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://uvh2umbgwb.feishu.cn/docs/doccnYVvyg3TdKp4Whnhz6424id&quot;&gt;Game Design Doc (Chinese)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Links to user testing notes, and discussion notes are included in the last page of the design doc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Game_Development" /><summary type="html">This is a retell of the Chinese traditional folklore The Legend of the White Snake. The game is developed for Tencent Institute of Games and is available for download at Apple App Store or by searching “白蛇·纸伞”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What2Yum Mobile App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What2Yum Mobile App" /><published>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum">&lt;p&gt;Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What2Yum allows you to swipe yes or no on a set of restaurant cards. You can send a link to your group chat. After your friends finish swiping. We will combine your preferences with your friends to help you guys make the final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/what2yum/appstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-notes&quot;&gt;Developers Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is developed by Eileen Chen, Kevin Wang, and Sebastian Yang. We used SwiftUI for frontend and Google Firebase for backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we went through 7 iterations and we did detailed documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint1.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 1: Ideation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint2.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 2: User experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint3.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 3: API &amp;amp; Prototyping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint4.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 4: Version 1 of the app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint5.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 5: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint6.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 6: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot;&gt;Sprint 7: Ship!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><category term="Highlights" /><summary type="html">Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Moochi Mobile Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Moochi Mobile Game" /><published>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi">&lt;p&gt;LittleMoochi is an app to help kids develop healthy earting habits by raising their own AI-powered digital pets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply take a picture of your food to feed Moochi. The more balanced the food, the happier Moochi, and the family are. And… don’t forget the cool prizes for helping Moochi grow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the the app now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.LittleMoochi.LittleMoochi.Beta&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/littlemoochi/id1489071692&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt; or search “LittleMoochi”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/littlemoochi/id1489071692&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/LittleMoochi/screenshot.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-environment&quot;&gt;Testing Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the testing environment for LittleMoochi’s marketing campaign mini game.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">LittleMoochi is an app to help kids develop healthy earting habits by raising their own AI-powered digital pets!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game Jam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game Jam" /><published>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts">&lt;p&gt;Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received Best Diversity Theme Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by: Grace Liu, Jan Orlowski, Jess Cao, Joseph Perrino, Sebastian Yang. (alphabetical order)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.SebLab.PairsOfHearts&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Website" /><published>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site">&lt;p&gt;This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#motivation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#first-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#second-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#two-point-five-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#third-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#future-plans&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are only interested in the technical portion, feel free to skip this part. : )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Websites are a great and interactive way to tell a story. When I’m reading a resume, I can only see a list of attributes as if I’m choosing a video game character by looking at his or her traits. But when I visit somebody’s website, I see a living human being with stories to tell. Hence, I want to present a more complete picture of myself to anyone who is interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I also want to have a place to record the interesting projects I’ve worked on. This idea came to me when during my high school graduation ceremony, a friend started talking about a research project we spent a few months working on in freshman year. I was confused because I don’t remember ever working on a research project with him. It wasn’t until that night did things starting to come back to me – it turned out we not only spent a few months on the project but also won a prize by doing a presentation on it but I totally forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 10 or 20 years, it would be a shame if I forget about these interesting projects and the cool people I worked with. Even though I understand visitors are not going to read all the posts I wrote, these posts serve as a personal archive for me to remind myself of the people I worked with and the stuff we achieve together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s dive into the development of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first iteration was developed in CMU67-250: The Information Systems Milieux. I developed an very simple website for a homework assignment.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The First Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first version is written in HTML, CSS, and JS. But as you can see, it looks very bad. If I hope to design an archive for my projects, I need it to look much better and more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Fun Fact: you can still visit this version of the site &lt;a href=&quot;/v18.3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the first iteration was unsalvageable. So I started redesigning the site from the ground up. I want the site to feel modern and interactive while being familiar to the user and can leave a strong impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about a week, every night after I finished my homework at around 10 pm, I would head to the Hunt Library. I spent one hour every night designing and developing this site. This version of the site looked pretty much the same as the one you see right now. The aesthetic and UI design you see right now are all designed and developed during that week. The only visual differences are that it had way fewer posts and there isn’t a &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;video game section&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Second Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site was also fully responsive on mobile devices because I used the Bootstrap CSS framework and tested responsiveness every step during development. I then deployed the site on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, it took me about 10 hours across 7 days to finish and deploy this site. In hindsight, I was surprised because I had almost no web design experience back then, especially with code. But I guess when you are passionate about something, nothing can stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month after the second iteration, I translated the site to Chinese and bought a new domain name. I essentially deployed the same site to a new GitHub account, but the texts are all in Chinese.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Chinese Site&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I ran into some trouble: whenever I want to add a new post, I need to edit the HTML code and working with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;text&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; a lot. And add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; whenever I want a new line. This is super slow and frustrating, especially when I have a lot of text.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with HTML&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months after the Chinese site went online, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to rebuild the site from the ground up. Jekyll is a static site generator. This means after I set up the framework for all the posts, I can just write the content in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, which is very similar to writing text in a txt file.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also allows me to translate between Chinese and English sites seamlessly. Right now no matter which post you are reading, if you click the Chinese button, you will be taken to the Chinese translation of that site instead of the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are developing a personal blog or portfolio site, I would highly recommend using Jekyll. It’s easy to learn, fun to use, and allows you to focus on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this site as a hub for all my projects. I will continue to update the site with my latest projects. It may come a little late as I’m only available during summer or winter breaks. But I’m looking forward to adding more projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may also consider rebuilding the site again with &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;. This will allow me to make the site more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I also added a new &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;Video Games&lt;/a&gt; section. But during my internship at Tencent Games and ByteDance Games, I played so many more games that I didn’t have time to update them all. I’m looking for a streamlined way to keep track of all the games I’ve played. I’m currently developing a full-stack website that will be my personal archive of games and books. The site should be able to export the database to a CSV file so that I can later do data analysis with R on the games I’ve played and books I’ve read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Web_Design" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><summary type="html">This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.</summary></entry></feed>