<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-15T21:48:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sebastian Yang</title><subtitle>This is the personal website for Sebastian Yang aka 杨毓恺.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What2Yum Mobile App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What2Yum Mobile App" /><published>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum">&lt;p&gt;Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What2Yum allows you to swipe yes or no on a set of restaurant cards. You can send a link to your group chat. After your friends finish swiping. We will combine your preferences with your friends to help you guys make the final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;(Link coming soon)Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-note&quot;&gt;Developers Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is developed by Eileen Chen, Kevin Wang, and Sebastian Yang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we went through 7 iterations and we did detailed documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint1.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 1: Ideation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint2.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 2: User experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint3.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 3: API &amp;amp; Prototyping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint4.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 4: Version 1 of the app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint5.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 5: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint6.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 6: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprint 7: Ship!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;privacy-policy&quot;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yukai Yang built the What2Yum app as a Free app. This SERVICE is provided by Yukai Yang at no cost and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at What2Yum unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;information-collection-and-use&quot;&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to device longitude and latitude to fetch the restaurants near you. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;log-data&quot;&gt;Log Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cookies&quot;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device’s internal memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;service-providers&quot;&gt;Service Providers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To facilitate our Service;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To provide the Service on our behalf;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To perform Service-related services; or&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-to-other-sites&quot;&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;childrens-privacy&quot;&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changes-to-this-privacy-policy&quot;&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 2020-12-16&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contact-us&quot;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at sebastianyang@outlook.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This privacy policy page was created at privacypolicytemplate.net and modified/generated by App Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Software_Engineer" /><summary type="html">Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Moochi Mobile Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Moochi Mobile Game" /><published>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi">&lt;p&gt;This is the testing environment for Little Moochi’s marketing campaign mini game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full game: &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.LittleMoochi.LittleMoochi.Beta&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/littlemoochi/id1489071692&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Design" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">This is the testing environment for Little Moochi’s marketing campaign mini game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game Jam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game Jam" /><published>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts">&lt;p&gt;Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received Best Diversity Theme Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by: Grace Liu, Jan Orlowski, Jess Cao, Joseph Perrino, Sebastian Yang. (alphabetical order)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.SebLab.PairsOfHearts&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Design" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Website" /><published>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site">&lt;p&gt;This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#motivation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#first-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#second-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#two-point-five-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#third-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#future-plans&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are only interested in the technical portion, feel free to skip this part. : )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Websites are a great and interactive way to tell a story. When I’m reading a resume, I can only see a list of attributes as if I’m choosing a video game character by looking at his or her traits. But when I visit somebody’s website, I see a living human being with stories to tell. Hence, I want to present a more complete picture of myself to anyone who is interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I also want to have a place to record the interesting projects I’ve worked on. This idea came to me when during my high school graduation ceremony, a friend started talking about a research project we spent a few months working on in freshman year. I was confused because I don’t remember ever working on a research project with him. It wasn’t until that night did things starting to come back to me – it turned out we not only spent a few months on the project but also won a prize by doing a presentation on it but I totally forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 10 or 20 years, it would be a shame if I forget about these interesting projects and the cool people I worked with. Even though I understand visitors are not going to read all the posts I wrote, these posts serve as a personal archive for me to remind myself of the people I worked with and the stuff we achieve together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s dive into the development of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first iteration was developed in CMU67-250: The Information Systems Milieux. I developed an very simple website for a homework assignment.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The First Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first version is written in HTML, CSS, and JS. But as you can see, it looks very bad. If I hope to design an archive for my projects, I need it to look much better and more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Fun Fact: you can still visit this version of the site &lt;a href=&quot;/v18.3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the first iteration was unsalvageable. So I started redesigning the site from the ground up. I want the site to feel modern and interactive while being familiar to the user and can leave a strong impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about a week, every night after I finished my homework at around 10 pm, I would head to the Hunt Library. I spent one hour every night designing and developing this site. This version of the site looked pretty much the same as the one you see right now. The aesthetic and UI design you see right now are all designed and developed during that week. The only visual differences are that it had way fewer posts and there isn’t a &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;video game section&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Second Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site was also fully responsive on mobile devices because I used the Bootstrap CSS framework and tested responsiveness every step during development. I then deployed the site on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, it took me about 10 hours across 7 days to finish and deploy this site. In hindsight, I was surprised because I had almost no web design experience back then, especially with code. But I guess when you are passionate about something, nothing can stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month after the second iteration, I translated the site to Chinese and bought a new domain name. I essentially deployed the same site to a new GitHub account, but the texts are all in Chinese.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Chinese Site&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I ran into some trouble: whenever I want to add a new post, I need to edit the HTML code and working with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;text&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; a lot. And add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; whenever I want a new line. This is super slow and frustrating, especially when I have a lot of text.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with HTML&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months after the Chinese site went online, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to rebuild the site from the ground up. Jekyll is a static site generator. This means after I set up the framework for all the posts, I can just write the content in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, which is very similar to writing text in a txt file.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also allows me to translate between Chinese and English sites seamlessly. Right now no matter which post you are reading, if you click the Chinese button, you will be taken to the Chinese translation of that site instead of the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are developing a personal blog or portfolio site, I would highly recommend using Jekyll. It’s easy to learn, fun to use, and allows you to focus on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this site as a hub for all my projects. I will continue to update the site with my latest projects. It may come a little late as I’m only available during summer or winter breaks. But I’m looking forward to adding more projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may also consider rebuilding the site again with &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;. This will allow me to make the site more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I also added a new &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;Video Games&lt;/a&gt; section. But during my internship at Tencent Games and ByteDance Games, I played so many more games that I didn’t have time to update them all. I’m looking for a streamlined way to keep track of all the games I’ve played. I’m currently developing a full-stack website that will be my personal archive of games and books. The site should be able to export the database to a CSV file so that I can later do data analysis with R on the games I’ve played and books I’ve read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Web_Design" /><summary type="html">This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boogieman VR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boogieman VR" /><published>2019-09-22T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR">&lt;p&gt;This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we designed a VR rhythm dancing game. Our original idea was to use ML and OpenCV so that the player can dance freely. Then we realized that is not gamey enough. The final result is a beat-saber-like node-hitting dancing game — as you hit the nodes, you begin to boogie. We knew we succeed when during the final demo, not only the person in VR is dancing, but the entire class spontaneously started dancing to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this 6-week project, I was the programmer in the team. We will go through 6 iterations for the game, developing a prototype for each week and presenting a demo on every Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXyuNnvKIBo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is made by (in alphabetical order): Ann Maria, Connie Chau, Kalpa Anjur, Lisa Lo, Carter Williams, and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for making this amazing dancing game a reality!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Design" /><category term="All" /><category term="Highlights" /><summary type="html">This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PuttPlot VR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PuttPlot VR" /><published>2019-09-21T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR">&lt;p&gt;Published on Oct 29, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we designed a golf-dating-sim called PuttPlot. Essentially, it is a Japanese-style dating sim but you choose your response by golfing the ball to the corresponding holes. This is both challenging and fun in that we need to simulate the 3D golfing gestures and physics in VR but at the same time tell an interesting story through 2D animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this 6-week project, I was the producer/programmer in the team. We will go through 6 iterations for the game, developing a prototype for each week and presenting a demo on every Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-1---brain-storming&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-1---brain-storming&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Brain Storming&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-2---pre-production&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-2---pre-production&quot;&gt;Week 2 - Pre-Production&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-1&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming-1&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#feedback-for-this-week&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-feedback-for-this-week&quot;&gt;Feedback for this week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-3---a-rough-week-&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-3---a-rough-week-&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Rough Week :(&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-2&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot;&gt;Programming - A Ramp is Built&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-4---play-testing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-4---play-testing&quot;&gt;Week 4 - Play-Testing&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing---a-small-bug&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing---a-small-bug&quot;&gt;Producing - A “Small” Bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-cont&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-cont&quot;&gt;Producing (CONT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Is on Fire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot;&gt;Week 5 - Things Are Finally Coming Together&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-3&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp is Never On&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned-1&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-6---release&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-6---release&quot;&gt;Week 6 - Release&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-4&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Broke, Again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned-2&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#credits&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1---brain-storming&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Brain Storming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of freedom in our project. The only requirement was that it needed to be a playable VR game inspired by any picnic game. And, of course, it needed to be developed within 6-week by a team of 5-6 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We formed our team on Friday, Aug 30th. On the next day, we had our first meeting. In the meeting, we spend about 4 hours talking about game ideas. Our discussion ranged from a technical-challenged beat-saber-style &lt;em&gt;Hall Ball&lt;/em&gt; to an Americano dark-humor game called &lt;em&gt;Catch With Dad&lt;/em&gt;. The game idea I proposed was an environmental-educational sandbox game called &lt;em&gt;Tree&lt;/em&gt; where you grow and destroy tress to impact global temperature. Sadly, it is a bit out of scope for a 6-week project so we didn’t end up running it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several rounds of voting, we ended up with the idea of a dating simulation golf game: &lt;em&gt;PuttPlot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we decided the game idea, we need to present a playable demo that following Friday. We cooperated by assigning tasks to each individual in the team. These were tasks like demo-board design, 2D arts and hitting mechanics. All individual task would be due by Wednesday night. And we would use Thursday night to integrate all the individual parts into a full game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our first demo, we just used rigid-body on the ball and added a collider on the golf club. We would add a force on the ball to the direction of the club whenever the ball was hit. So Unity physics will handle the collision and how golf ball would fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did pretty well for our first week. Our demo is working and the class seems to like it. We also received a lot of constructive feedback.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Concept Art for the game&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-2---pre-production&quot;&gt;Week 2 - Pre-Production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get things going, we did a lot of pre-production work this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-1&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we decided on the three pillars of the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laughter: the game should be very very funny / subverted expectations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engaging stories: player’s decisions matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board configuration connect to dialogue options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our game mainly consisted of two parts: a golfing mechanics and an intriguing story. So for the second week, our writer Gus worked on the story and ended up with a bunch of index card full of funny stories he wrote. Our artiest Angelina worked on more concepts and character art. Our programmer Carter and Ann worked on driving golf. And I worked on the board design and producing work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still used the integrate-on-Thursday-present-on-Friday approach. Since a lot of the work we did is preproduction, the final demo we presented on Friday for this week isn’t that much different from the previous week.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-story.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-story.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Draft story tree for the game&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-1&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we try to mimic how golf ball in the real world works. In real life, the golf ball will not fly away immediately after contact with the club, but will instead be lifted a bit by the club and the fly away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we try to do that in the game by adding the ball to be a child object of the club immediately after contact so that it would stick to the club. After the ball move up to the direction of the swing for a few milliseconds, we will release the ball and adding a force to make it fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is good but the final result wasn’t as successful as we would want it to be. The ball still moves too fast and didn’t land on the location you would expect it to land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-for-this-week&quot;&gt;Feedback for this week&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same as last week, we received a lot of feedback after our demo on Friday and we boiled down to four points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ball was too fast/not visible enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text looked bad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board UI needed work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driving doesn’t feel good. Need a RAMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we forget to record gameplay video in the first two iterations so you won’t be able to see them.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-game.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-game.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The second iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-3---a-rough-week-&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Rough Week :(&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our third iteration of the game, things started to get a bit difficult. We had the Technical Opportunities Conference this week, which is the biggest career fair on CMU each year. Many teammates spent all their free time on Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday in that event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-2&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essentially meant our Wednesday checkpoint was not met. So we ended up trying to scramble everything together at the last minute. Carter, Gus and I stayed at Hunt Library basement until after midnight. Even after that, the version we submitted was still very buggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed several levels(boards) for the game. But because we failed to get the dialogue transition working in time. We never got a chance to transit to the new levels. Therefore, our demo on Friday was not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot;&gt;Programming - A Ramp is Built&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good thing was we got a working ramp. One of the feedback that we received was that just driving the ball to the board did’t feel good. We solved this by adding an acceleration ramp. In this case, the player only needs to putt the ball to the ramp and ball will fly up to the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, we will do better next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Sep 28, 2019.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week3-ramp.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week3-ramp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The ramp&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-4---play-testing&quot;&gt;Week 4 - Play-Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are officially passing the halfway point of our project but we still haven’t got the core game loop ready. So there is only one goal this week: nail down the game loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing---a-small-bug&quot;&gt;Producing - A “Small” Bug&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning from last week’s experience, we tried to add more checkpoints and iterations throughout the week. Instead of only integrating on Thursday night, we integrated and play-test on Tuesday night and integrated again on Wednesday and Thursday nights. This meant we could at least iterate two times in one week: one for play-testing on Tuesday and one for the demo on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, we were fixing bugs while inviting people to play-test. Near the end of the play-test session, we fixed all the bugs that are left from last week, especially a bug that will prevent the dialogue from moving to the next board and options.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-environment.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-environment.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Week4 the environment behind the player&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we found a smaller bug. Instead of creating a new ball and destroy old ones, we cycled through golf balls. This meant there are only 10 golf balls in total in the game. We created these ball at the beginning of the game and when you hit the ball with index 9, the ball with index 0 will come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since we only changed its transform.location, there were still forces on the ball if the player went through all the balls very quickly. Since we were play-testing, there was no time to rewrite the script, we just changed the number of balls from 10 to 100000000 in the editor, thinking there is no way a player could go through 100000000 balls that quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the play button, without thinking twice. But apparently, initializing 100000000 game objects in a for-loop at the beginning of the game is a bad idea …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unity stopped responding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were thinking: “Cool, I’ll just have to reopen Unity and change the number back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we forgot to save the scene before entering that huge number…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So all the modifications we made that night in the scene was gone…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-cont&quot;&gt;Producing (CONT)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All was not lost. We integrated again on Wednesday to revert all the changes we made on Tuesday. And we also integrated on Thursday to add more features like background, voice and more dialogue. At around 11:20 pm on Thursday, when we tried to integrate all the dialogue scriptable objects and voice to our main game, the game broke again because my teammates were using the older version of the event system (the one from last week) and we changed the system since then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent 10-20 mins trying to fix this issue. This meant we only have 20 mins left to integrate. We have to make a hard choice, either we could put all the dialogue in so the player can play a full game without voice acting, or we could put the dialogue and voice acting for the first scene so the player can experience a shorter but complete game loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the producer, it was a hard choice for me to make. Because both sides have spent a lot of time tonight working and both would like their stuff in the game. But I decided to go with the latter because a short snapshot of our game can provide people a better understanding of the game and what the game would look like once it is finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Is on Fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We moved the golf ball’s location around and didn’t have time to recalibrate the boosting ramp. So in our demo on Friday, when our TA Adrian tested the game, the ramp boosted too much and he overshot the ball a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something can go wrong, it will go wrong… So save files periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Oct 5, 2019.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-player-view.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-player-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Week4 Player's View&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot;&gt;Week 5 - Things Are Finally Coming Together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With two weeks to go, we finally nailed down our core game loop. This week we got all the major elements integrated: story, putting, environment and some voice acting in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-3&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the organizational changes, we made last week worked, we again play-tested our game on Tuesday night and integrate it on Wednesday and Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because our game is dialogue-focused, once we got the dialogue system set up the game would work decently. So this week we saw all the previous debugging and coding efforts finally paid off (special thanks to our lead programmer Carter). We also added a chat history on the sides of the player, so that the player can see the previous chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp is Never On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that in week 3 we added a ramp？And in week 4 the ramp makes the player overshot a lot? This was actually kind of wired because in week 3 the ramp would not cause as much overshooting as it did in week 4. So this week we try to solve that problem by recalibrating the ramp and the ball’s landing location on the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire evening with a headset on in our VR game while Carter tweaked parameters for the ramp. Each time he tweaked something, I would the ramp and see where the ball lands. And each time we do that, we would convince ourselves that we are almost there, just a few more tweaks to go.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week5-recalibrate.gif&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week5-recalibrate.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Recalibrating the Ramp&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, we were a bit frustrated because no matter how we tweak the parameters, the ramp would always overshoot. Wait a minute, no matter how we change the parameters … the outcome would not change… it could only be … but that’s impossible …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, the ramp’s collider was never turned on. The collider that was supposed to detect and boost the ball, the collider that we thought we were changing was never on. We must have turned it off during some testing and forgot to turn it back on. Because it was off, it had absolutely no effects in the game. And we just spent about an hour trying to “fix” it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we turn the collider on, everything worked decently. In our demo on Friday, our guest, a naive play-tester, seemed impressed by our game, especially how easy the putting feels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned-1&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains, no matter how improbable, must be the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Oct 11, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-6---release&quot;&gt;Week 6 - Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our final week to work on the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-4&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After play-testing the game on Tuesday, we listed 10-12 additional features and improvements we wanted to add to the game. Our biggest challenge this week was getting all the voice and dialogue lines in. As I have said before, once we got the main dialogue system working, it would just be a matter of click and drag all the files in. But since we were trying to create a funny dating simulator, we have a long story (consisted of 7 short stories with branches). It took us a long time to put all the dialogue lines and its’ corresponding voice acting in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 9:30 pm on Thursday, we managed to get the whole game working (without voice acting). I play-tested the entire game while our writer Gus was putting voices into the scriptable objects for each dialogue. Surprisingly, because we had too many jokes and stories, it took me a good 20-30 minutes to finish the entire game. The version we had right now would be our last-known-good in case things went south.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished adding all the voices acting in at around 10:50 - 11:00 pm, about one hour before the deadline. Then, things went south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Broke, Again&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programming section of this article was created to talk about the technical challenges we faced during the game development. But I just realized almost all of them are actually about the ramp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 11:00 pm, one hour before the deadline, we decided to recalibrate the ramp (again). This was because we added a tutorial to this game. The tutorial would ask the player to shoot the far left and far right of the board, so that players would know how to control the putting. But, currently, shooting to the side would cause a bug on the ramp, making the golf ball never land on the board. We never notice this problem last week because we did not add the tutorial until this week. So with one hour to go, we started debugging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carter and I started our classic duel: He would tweak different parameters on the ramp and I would be in the headset hitting the golf ball and giving him feedback. But we encountered the same problem: no matter how we tweak the parameters, the boosting effect would not be activated for all the balls landing on the far sides of the ramp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked the collider, yes, it was on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 11:45 pm, the atmosphere was tense. On the one hand, hitting the ball up through the ramp was our core game mechanics, we have an obligation to make it work. On the other hand, we had no idea whether we could solve this bug or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 11:50 pm, we found the bug. It was one line of code in the ramp’s script that narrowed the range of checking collision. After we simply commented it out, things worked beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, we presented our game to the whole class. Even though we still had some problems with the putting, the play-test went well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I made a mistake here. I should have built the game after we added all the voice acting and before we started debugging the ramp. This is because our last-know-good was the version built around 9:30 pm. It did not have all the voice acting in. Had the debugging effort failed, and the game fails to compile before midnight, all the effort of recording the voice acting and adding it to the game would be lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned-2&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last-Known-Good is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhujQxwyqC4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time working on a game as producer. It is really a learning experience for me. I am very grateful to have a supportive team. I’d really like to give a shout-out to our programmer Carter Williams, our writer Gus Saalfeld and our artiest Angelina Shi. This game would not be possible without their’s and all our teammates contribution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Game_Design" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">Published on Oct 29, 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BigSkinny</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/BigSkinny" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BigSkinny" /><published>2019-08-13T16:00:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-13T16:00:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/BigSkinny</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/BigSkinny">&lt;p&gt;This is the term project for CMU 67-250: The Information Systems Milieux. In this TP, we were the consulting team SQL Injection and tasked to rebrand the slim wallet company Big Skinny by analyzing its current UX and marketing strategy. Throughout the process, we redesigned Big Skinny’s website, outlined a new database structure and write out a detailed case analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two weeks of work, my team not only received an A for our deliverables, we also received the 2019 ISM Award for Best Case Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that we were not formally employed by Big Skinny. All the information about Big Skinny in this article are public knowledge available on the internet.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Ad.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Ad.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Big Skinny's Ad&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#background&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#problems&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-problems&quot;&gt;Problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-proposal&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-our-proposal&quot;&gt;Our Proposal&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#marketing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-marketing&quot;&gt;Marketing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#new-website&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-new-website&quot;&gt;New website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interactive-wallet-selection-guide&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-interactive-wallet-selection-guide&quot;&gt;Interactive Wallet Selection Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-user-story&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-a-user-story&quot;&gt;A User Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#credits&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Skinny is an e-commerce wallet company that sells thin wallets. Because of the unique material it uses, the company can produce surprisingly thin and lightweight wallets that are also water resistant and can be machine washed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems like a great product, but in reality, this company is facing plummeting sales and its yelp page is filled with negative one-star reviews.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Bad_Reviews.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Bad_Reviews.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what went wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;problems&quot;&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon reviewing the company, my team and I concluded three major problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one is its bad website design. It’s hard to navigate and includes too much text and options. You can expereince it first-hand &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigskinny.net&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigskinny.net&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/index.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Home Page of Big Skinny&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is their front page when we took over. As you can see, different components were not aligned, tags and buttons are confusing (what does “CARD CASES + $ CLIPS” even means??). I hate to say this but the whole site left me with an impression of a high school project done at the last minute. Because of the bad user interface design, the conversion rate for somebody redirected to this website through online ads is guaranteed to be low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second problem is its lack of a target customer group. In its website, it tries to target men, women, travelers, police officers, teenagers, businessmen, and women, as well as random customer group with products like “Paper watch” and “Stainless Steel Mesh Wallet Comb” that doesn’t make any sense for a wallet company to sell.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/page.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/page.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Skinny is the textbook classic company that tries to fit all markets. By providing more than 40+ Wallets for people to choose and tons of unnecessary accessories, the company try to please everyone and got no one in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third one is poor database management. In the yelp page, many people left a negative review because of an incident in 2010. In this incident, more than 4000 people ordered wallets through Big Skinny’s website. But because of a “glitch in an online promotion” as Big Skinny CEO Kiril Alexandrov put it, most of the wallets were given for free. Technical difficulties with promotion coupons appeared multiple times ever since, as can be seen in 2013 and 2017. This can be attributed to bad database structure and management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-proposal&quot;&gt;Our Proposal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve Big Skinny’s sales, we first need to rebrand the company. Thus, we identified a target customer group: young travelers. This is because big skinny’s waterproof thin wallet fit the need of travelers and hikers. Then, we identified three major problems with its current website: lengthy words, disorganized layout, too many choices to narrow down to one product. And by deploying online marketing campaigns directly targeting young travelers and redesigning our website to provide a youth-centered user experience that can attract and assist young travelers in buying and selecting wallets. Finally, we come up with a new database relationship system that can hopefully avoid further coupon problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;marketing&quot;&gt;Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To target young gen Z travelers, we initiated the “Built for the Courageous” online marketing campaign. As a part of this campaign, Big Skinny will need at least one person dedicated solely to consistently creating new content and synthesizing customer testimonials for future advertisements. Part of this campaign will include new media for all platforms, such as a Facebook video ad to target and draw in the young traveler demographic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-website&quot;&gt;New website&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we allured customer with ads to our website, we need to provide an easy-to-use user experience. Thus, we first re-designed the website by organizing its information architecture in a clean and easy to follow manner. We designed a clear navigation bar and cut down words in the index page from 200 words to around 50 words while keeping essential information. By accompanied them with images, we can make them more readable for the customer.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/New_Index.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/New_Index.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;interactive-wallet-selection-guide&quot;&gt;Interactive Wallet Selection Guide&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to help customers narrow their choices from 40+ wallet designs to one wallet, we designed an interactive wallet selection guide.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Selection_Guide.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/Selection_Guide.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-user-story&quot;&gt;A User Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say Jack is a 20-year-old college graduate, While browsing Facebook one day, he saw a short video about this amazingly slim wallet. This video is actually a Facebook ad we bought in the online marketing campaign. By the end of the video, he saw a line says “Build for the courageous”. As a traveler, he was inspired to click the link to go to our website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon visiting our website, the first thing he saw is this inspiring image and as he scrolled down he saw all the advantages of Big Skinny wallets. Just as he was about to buy one, he saw the wallet selection guide and clicked it. There, he can select his preferences and the site will provide recommendations.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/question.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/question.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wow, these recommendations seem great. let me check out this wallet”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the product info page, we simplified all the product information. So, customers can learn more about the wallet quickly and place an order quickly.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/recommand.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/BigSkinny/recommand.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“This looks great. I will take it!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the end of one transaction, but not the end of our relationship with this customer. Using our database system, a week after Jack bought the first wallet, we will recommend a second category of wallet, such as a leather wallet different from the one customer originally purchased, and advertise it in an email saying, “One for outdoors and one for indoors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, by integrating market research, database design, and website design, this solution will emphasize Big Skinny’s strengths and improved customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the two weeks of our term project, my role is sort of like the “product manger” in the team. I set up the overall goal and communicate with each individual about their design, provide them with feedback, make sure the production timeline is working and keep track of the scope of our term project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the four of us cannot meet frequently, I coordinate the team to make sure we are all on the same page and the Executive summary, web prototype, ERD and our presentation are tightly integrated. On the other hand, my friend Christine, Megan and Jonathan are responsible for the actual work. Thank you for all the good work!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Web_Design" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">This is the term project for CMU 67-250: The Information Systems Milieux. In this TP, we were the consulting team SQL Injection and tasked to rebrand the slim wallet company Big Skinny by analyzing its current UX and marketing strategy. Throughout the process, we redesigned Big Skinny’s website, outlined a new database structure and write out a detailed case analysis.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">15112</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/fall/15112" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="15112" /><published>2019-08-13T14:41:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-13T14:41:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/fall/15112</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/fall/15112">&lt;p&gt;This project is dedicated to Scott Chen For being my “sametable” in high school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the term project for CMU 15-112: Fundamentals of Programming and Computer Science. This is the first video game I ever developed. It is programmed in Python with pygame package and is a recreation of the flash game Tank Trouble. I chose to recreate Tank Trouble because I used to play this game a lot with my friends in high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page serves as a breakdown of the game so future 15112 students can refer to without going over the boring codes I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see a 3 mins snapshot of the game here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt; &lt;iframe width=&quot;866&quot; height=&quot;487&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qkijJCenGDE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#overall-structure&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-overall-structure&quot;&gt;Overall Structure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#multiplayer-mode&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-multiplayer-mode&quot;&gt;Multiplayer Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#game-ai-mode&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-game-ai-mode&quot;&gt;Game AI Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#easter-mode&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-easter-mode&quot;&gt;Easter Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#areas-for-improvement&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-areas-for-improvement&quot;&gt;Areas for Improvement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall-structure&quot;&gt;Overall Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game has 7 different scenes: StartScreen, SinglePlayerMode, TwoPlayerMode, ThreePlayerMode, InstructionsScreen, RankScreen, and EasterMode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because pygame doesn’t support scenes switching like the ones in Unity, I wrote some scene switching codes that basically calls to different redrawAll or timerFired when in a different mode. I think this method is covered in class as well so I will not elaborate further here. You can learn more here:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.krivers.net/15112-s18/notes/notes-animations-demos.html&quot;&gt; Mode Demo &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Mode_Demo.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Mode_Demo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Mode Demo&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multiplayer-mode&quot;&gt;Multiplayer Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local two-player multiplayer mode is the MVP for this game. The tricky part is how to check collision between tanks and the map as well as bullets and the map. The map is generated as a png image with walls as black pixels and passage as transparent background (zero alpha channel). The tank is just a sprite image of a cartoon tank.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Two_Player_Mode.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Two_Player_Mode.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Two Player Mode&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many friends of mine, who are in spring 2019 112 class, try to use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;
pygame.sprite.collide(self,map)&lt;/code&gt;
in their games. This may not work because sprite.collide treats the map as a sprite aka as a whole image. Since the map is below your game object (tanks in my case), your game object will always collide with the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, there is a neat function called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pygame.sprite.collide_mask(self,map)&lt;/code&gt;. This would work properly because this function creates a “mask” for the map. Namely, it creates a new “image” with the pixels that are of non-zero alpha channels only. Hence, in my case, only the black walls will be considered for collision, but the transparent passage will not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing you might want to look out for in MVP is the frame rate. In my first prototype, the bullets speed per second is faster than the frame rate per second. Due to high speed, it can move to pass the width of the wall before the next collision check. Hence, the bouncy wall effect I wanted cannot be achieved. At first, I thought this was a programming problem, so I kept trying to tweak the collision method. So just beware that frame rate can mess with your collision test.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Three_Player_Mode.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Three_Player_Mode.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Three Player Mode&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished one tank without AI in the first iteration. After finishing the two-player mode in the second iteration, I added a three-player mode in the third iteration. The third player will use a mouse to navigate and right click to shoot bullets. This is not very hard to implement once you got all the base code ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-ai-mode&quot;&gt;Game AI Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, this is the hardest part of the game. I need to program an AI tank that can navigate, shoot and avoid bullets. Theoretically, if I have the map stored in a 2D list, I can just use a backtrack function and update AI’s path periodically. The algorithms would not be very hard to write. The problem, though, is that I did not store the map in a 2D list.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/15112/AI_Mode.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/15112/AI_Mode.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;AI Mode&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to simplify my MVP, I initially used a photoshopped image of the map. During my second iteration, I cannot think of an efficient way to generate a map using backtracking. This is because I need to avoid close containment of any size so that the tanks will not be trapped in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to keep the project moving, I chose to avoid this path. In my second iteration, I simply make the AI tank simple turn right every time it hits a wall. This will make the AI tank appears to be moving around. As you may have guessed, the downside is the tank sometimes will be trap in a circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my third iteration, I write a “ray casting” function. Basically, I will send out 8 different bullets to 8 direction periodically. These bullets will not be drawn. This ray cast can let the tank know which direction has more space and which direction is a dead end. The tank can then make a decision about turning base on this information.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Ray_Casting.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/15112/Ray_Casting.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Ray Casting&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fine-tuning for a long time, the game AI works pretty well. I feel like you can always try to come up with creative ways to implement game AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;easter-mode&quot;&gt;Easter Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fourth iteration, I added some powerups that change tank size and speed, a ranking screen that stores past scores locally, as well as an Easter mode. You can trigger the Easter mode by messing around in the starter screen. Feel free to play around and try to break the game  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;areas-for-improvement&quot;&gt;Areas for Improvement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I have more time, I would try to come up with a map generation algorithm. This will enable the game to have random maps and the game AI can also be more interesting. It would also be fun to add a mode where two AI tanks fight each other.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Design" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">This project is dedicated to Scott Chen For being my “sametable” in high school</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transease</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/spring/Transease" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transease" /><published>2019-08-10T14:37:52-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T14:37:52-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/spring/Transease</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2018/spring/Transease">&lt;p&gt;In my third year in high school, we have a new teacher named Mark coming from England. But the problem is that he cannot speak Chinese at all. So, when he needed to rent a house or talk to the locals, he needed us to help translate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking. Wouldn’t it be so nice if every time people need translation, somebody can just magically show up and help them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being inspired by Uber, I come up with a real-time human translation app that can achieve just that at a low price. By working with my friends Tony Lian and Yujie Wang, we came up with a prototype and won the world top 50 in the 2018 Microsoft Imagine Cup Big Idea Challenge. We are also the only team from mainland China that receive such prize in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/award.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/award.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Don't ask my why they put my last name first. I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#problem&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#solution&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#one-user-story&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-one-user-story&quot;&gt;One User Story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#prototype&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#potential-development&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-potential-development&quot;&gt;Potential Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#credits&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;problem&quot;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been to 17 different countries, but I can only speak two languages. Hence, trying to communicate across different languages have always been a problem I wanted to solve. Currently, people tend to use free online translation apps like Google translate or hire an expensive translator. The problem is these translation apps are inaccurate. Here is one example. Even though the Chinese “能穿多少穿多少” is the same, it actually has totally different meanings in different settings. In the following case, it actually means “It’s hot, wear as little clothes as you can.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/Translation_Error.jpg&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/Translation_Error.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Translation Error&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for hiring translators, well, it’s way too expensive. So, I want to see if there is a middle ground that can make a translation by human affordable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uber fascinates me because its core idea is so simple, yet it solves a huge problem in our society. If Uber can connect available drivers with people who need rides, why couldn’t we connect available translators with people who need translation service?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-user-story&quot;&gt;One User Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jieke is a Chinese traveler visiting the US. He wanted to talk to a local shop owner for about 10 minutes about their business, but he cannot speak English. So, he opens our app Transease in his phone and clicks “Translate”.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our system will search for whoever is available and connect them with Jieke&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say on the other side of the globe, an American exchange student Jack just finishes his class in a Chinese university. He can speak English and Chinese and have about 10 minutes available. He can open our app and click “start receiving jobs”.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/2.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our system will then connect Jack with Jieke, and let Jack translate for Jieke via voice call. After the service, Jack will receive a small fee from Jieke. And , Jieke can rate his experience with Jack and continue his travel until he needs translation service again.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/3.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototype&quot;&gt;Prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure this will actually work, I came up with an MVP. I asked 6 friends who can speak Chinese and English to help out. I put their contact info in a table showing their available timeslots. I also recruited two foreign teachers who cannot speak Chinese very well to be our test subjects. Basically, in the MVP, whenever the subjects need translation service, he or she can look up the table and call the number that is available during that timeslot. The person who is available will translate for them via the phone call.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/Call_Table.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/Call_Table.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Call Table&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This MVP is like a proof of concept to show translation over voice call actually works. We received many feedbacks. And we try to address most of the problem in our first prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the high costs of developing apps for different platforms, our first prototype is a website that is optimized for mobile users. It has login and voice calling features. We added more features such as ratings and video chat as we went. This prototype helped us win the Big Idea Challenge In 2018 Microsoft Imagine Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;potential-development&quot;&gt;Potential Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the middle stage of our project, I realize a more significant problem. Our app can easily be replaced if the translation algorithm is good enough. And since people are used to using free translation apps, how can we encourage them to spend a few more bucks to use a human translator?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I have more time, these are the areas I would try to improve. First, I would like to hold another user testing this time asking people to actually pay for the service. Then, through more iterations, I would like to improve our app’s UI design and a better payment system. Moreover, in the future, if the app does work, we will have the recording of millions of minutes of translation. This amount of data may help us train an algorithm that can outperform most of the free translation service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sadly, we stop the project after we parted ways to different colleges.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/bg1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Transease/bg1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;br /&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual app development is all done by my friend Tony Lian and Yujie Wang. Tony is responsible for back end and Yujie for front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than coming up with the idea, my role in this project is providing feedbacks across iterations and making sure the scope of our project is working. I am also responsible for user testing, market research, surveys, and pitching the idea to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Entrepreneurship" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Marketing" /><summary type="html">In my third year in high school, we have a new teacher named Mark coming from England. But the problem is that he cannot speak Chinese at all. So, when he needed to rent a house or talk to the locals, he needed us to help translate.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">APA</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2015/fall/APA" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="APA" /><published>2019-08-10T13:57:52-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-10T13:57:52-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2015/fall/APA</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2015/fall/APA">&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, animals should be treated ethically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Not being an extreme activist, I focus my work on boycotting animal acrobatics. I was elected the president of our school’s Animal Protection Association in 2016. Then, I lead a team of 15 students to initiate the “Not Born to Perform” campaign to stop animal acrobatics in Xiamen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout our campaign, I organized charity sales and class presentations. At the peak of our campaign, we argued with local government representatives to stop school trips to a local animal circus and we held charity show at 5 different public areas in my city at the same time with over 120 student volunteers, donating all the money we raised to PETA Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our story:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/APA/sign.JPG&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/APA/sign.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt; &quot;I promise I will never visit animal circuses.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#phase-1-in-classrooms&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-phase-1-in-classrooms&quot;&gt;Phase 1: In Classrooms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#phase-2-on-campus&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-phase-2-on-campus&quot;&gt;Phase 2: On Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#phase-3-in-society&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-phase-3-in-society&quot;&gt;Phase 3: In Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-1-in-classrooms&quot;&gt;Phase 1: In Classrooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my firm belief that people’s joy should not be based on animals’ suffering. Thus, I was never fond of the idea of animal acrobatics. So I felt very uncomfortable when I learned my local government decided to invest about 100 million RMB (15 million USD) in building the largest animal circus in the world at my city, the “Ling Ling International Circus City” (厦门灵玲国际马戏城).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision has already been made by the government. Since demonstrations and appeals were not an option in my city, I focused on dissuading the public to visit. The easiest group of people I could reach was my schoolmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I wrote a speech and taught my teammates at the APA how to present. Then we talked to the school officials and presented our speed at each classroom. In the end, we received more than 100 signatures from students who vowed they would never visit animal circuses.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/APA/sign2.JPG&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/APA/sign2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Signatures from students&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-2-on-campus&quot;&gt;Phase 2: On Campus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after our initial campaign, our local government’s education department decided to make Ling Ling circus as the destination of many public schools’ school trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying we were not happy would be an understatement. We were furious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I split my team into two groups. One group focus on reaching out to school and government officials to try to change the destination. But we knew the chances were slim since the local government was one of the investors of the circus. The other group focused on campus-wide charity sales to raise awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed many merchandises and sold them at our on-campus charity sale. And we went back to the classroom again to pitch our idea and dissuade students from participating. But since there were only 2 school trips in our 3 years in high school, it was hard to dissuade students. Thus, I reframed the talk from “No Circus” to “My Last Trip to Circus”. We asked students to think what how do they feel if they were the animals and ask them to make this their first and final trip to animal circuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row text-center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch1.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch1.JPG&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    Designed by Us
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch2.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch2.JPG&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    Charity sale
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col-4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch3.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/merch3.JPG&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    Yep, that's me
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-3-in-society&quot;&gt;Phase 3: In Society&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we did not manage to change the destination for our school trip. Many people, including myself, ended up going to the circus. This should be the end of our campaign, but, as you may have known, giving up is never an option for me. I wanted to raise more people’s awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, I was also one of the chief organizers of the 2017 Amoy Youth Elite Summit. Bridging the gap between different organizations have always been my thing. Thus, I wanted to motivate the participants of the Summit to help us with our campaign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the summit, I gave 50 RMB(7.4 USD) to each team as their initial fund. Each team has 3 days to plan out an executable plan to advocate for the rejecting animal circuses. And they would act out their plan on the fourth day. The participation was, of course, voluntary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was like a little experiment because I had no idea what they can come up within 3 days and how many people will even show up. But it turned out to be a great success. On the day of the event, about 120 students joined our event as organizers. We held charity sales and charity shows at two shopping districts (ZhongShang Road中山路, ShaPoWei沙坡尾), a shopping mall (SM), a public park (WuYi Squar五一广场) and our school at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we educated many pedestrians and received more than 500 signatures. We raised about 3600 RMB in four hours. And the budget for the whole event was only 550 RMB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/poster3.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/poster3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/posts1.PNG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/posts1.PNG&quot; class=&quot;w-75&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/posts2.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/posts2.png&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/sales.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/sales.JPG&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/cert.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/cert.jpg&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/APA/signitures.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/images/projects/APA/signitures.png&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;


&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Event_Planning" /><category term="All" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Non_Profits" /><summary type="html">From my perspective, animals should be treated ethically. Not being an extreme activist, I focus my work on boycotting animal acrobatics. I was elected the president of our school’s Animal Protection Association in 2016. Then, I lead a team of 15 students to initiate the “Not Born to Perform” campaign to stop animal acrobatics in Xiamen.</summary></entry></feed>