<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-21T15:06:12-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Sebastian Yang</title><subtitle>This is the personal website for Sebastian Yang aka 杨毓恺.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Artlas Mobile AR App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artlas Mobile AR App" /><published>2021-05-20T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-20T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/Artlas">&lt;p&gt;Point your camera to a building, and Artlas will put its name in front of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time when you want to find the name of a building, no need to circle all the way to the front to read its name or zoom in and out on your Maps app. Just point and click with Artlas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is currently available only in parts of certain cities. When the time is right, head out and see if it works in your area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is developed by Sebastian Yang for fun.
Built with Swift, ARKit, RealityKit, MapKit, UIKit, and CoreLocation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/artlas-ar-building-names/id1567798806&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/artlas-ar-building-names/id1567798806&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/Artlas/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first AR app. I learned a lot of cool technical stuff using ARkit, but here are some of my main takeaways that might be helpful to anyone developing AR apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-user-guidance-and-showing-actionable-steps-in-ar-are-critical&quot;&gt;1. User Guidance and Showing Actionable Steps in AR are Critical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most apps only need to guide the user once at the beginning and most actionable steps are implicit and self-explanatory: you see the Wifi bar goes down, you will move closer to the WIFI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not in AR. In AR, we have to constantly guide and inform the user about the current state of the app such as tracking availability, accuracy, and actionable steps to improve it. In AR Geotracking, we also need to tell the user why the app fail to localize the user and how to solve it (trees blocking the view? Move too fast? No buildings in view? etc). A case in point is, in Artlas, if the user looks down, the app will explicitly prompt the user to look up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guidances are critical to ensure a smooth user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-universal-icons-in-ar-is-an-area-for-exploration&quot;&gt;2. Universal Icons in AR is an Area for Exploration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, hopefully, there will be universal icons in AR, similar to the WiFi and battery icons, that represent different states and implicitly tells the user what to do, especially for common information like the tracking accuracy and actions like move the camera to scan the environment. If so, we won’t have to put an overlay text over the camera view every time we want to guide the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-be-thorough-in-reasons-for-using-sensitive-information&quot;&gt;3. Be Thorough in Reasons for Using Sensitive Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of Artlas was actually rejected because when explaining the reasons for using the user location, I only mentioned I use it for finding nearby buildings but forgot to mention it is also being used for ARkit’s Geotracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, being explicit and thorough in reasons for using sensitive information, is beneficial for both the user’s understanding and the developer’s shipping schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;under-the-hood&quot;&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artlas uses Apple ARKit’s Geotracking feature. It uses your GPS coordinates and the image stream captured from your camera to understand where you are in the real world. Then it searches for nearby places of interest using MapKit and finds the nearest one in the direction you are pointing towards when you hit the button. Then it will generate a 3D text object using RealityKit and place it at the location of the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We value privacy so we do not store any user information. Everything is done locally using Apple’s native APIs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><category term="AR_VR" /><summary type="html">Point your camera to a building, and Artlas will put its name in front of it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FitSaber VR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FitSaber VR" /><published>2021-05-19T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-19T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/FitSaber">&lt;p&gt;Promoting Cognitive Engagement and Physical Activity in Virtual Reality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology use grows at an exponential rate and sedentary behavior increases in the wake of the global pandemic, evidence-based practices promoting both physical activity and cognitive engagement are needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is the development of the research-based “making” portion of an experimental study to examine the effects on cognitive skills in 18- to 23- year-olds from varying virtual reality (VR) conditions. This study uses a between-subject design with participants recruited through the university Psychology Subject Pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conditions are experimentally modified VR rhythm games. Participants are presented a stream of approaching directional blocks and respond by moving their arms left, right, up, down, or diagonal depending on the direction of an arrow on the target block using a corresponding saber. There will be meticulous manipulations to the amount of physical activity and cognitive demands for each condition. Participants will be randomly assigned to one of four conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise (Standard) Condition: high physical activity + low cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combined (Standard + Rule Switch) Condition: high physical activity + high cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cognitive (Sedentary + Rule Switch) Condition: low physical activity + high cognitive demands;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;or Control (Sedentary Standard) Condition: low physical activity + low cognitive demands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants in all conditions train for 45 minutes total (9 songs total) with 15 minutes of practice beforehand. Participants’ cognitive skills will be assessed at pretest and posttest before and after training using standard neurocognitive measures and questionnaires. This project shows the development of the conditions, game features, and outcome measures utilized to assess cognitive skills in young adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official testing will start in the fall of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is sponsored by Facebook Reality Lab and CMU SURG Grant for VR equipment. Facebook and SURG did not participate in the design and implementation of the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hTGAXOeDxpU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, I had the honor to be the VR Team Lead coordinating the development of the VR software that we used for research. Here are some of my takeaways from this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-be-comfortable-with-ambiguity&quot;&gt;1. Be Comfortable with Ambiguity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychology research in VR is an emerging field. There weren’t a lot of precedents we can refer to. Hence, we spent an entire semester pilot testing. We tried many different conditions using the original Beat Saber game and our paper prototypes to narrow down to the aforementioned four conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When conducting research, feeling comfortable embracing ambiguity and uncertainty is an essential skill, especially in the field of VR, where few researchers have ever set foot on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-visualize-the-work-in-progress&quot;&gt;2. Visualize the Work In Progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanban board is a great tool to visualize the work in progress. Unlike a production line, where the bottleneck can be identified easily by seeing stuff piling up, a software engineering team’s work in progress is not visible. However, it is critical for the leader in the team to understand the current state of the project and where the bottleneck is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, by using Kanban to show the work in progress and deadlines, I had a complete understanding of where we were and where we were going. We were able to build and ship the game with all the core functionalities within one semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-use-spatial-audio-to-make-vr-immersive&quot;&gt;3. Use Spatial Audio to Make VR Immersive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having every sound coming from an actual source is one of the keys to an immersive experience in VR. In our FitSaber, the satisfying slicing sound will come from the location where the block is sliced. VR has the ability to make the players completely believe in the world they are in, and the lack of positional audio will ruin the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;under-the-hood&quot;&gt;Under the Hood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we re-created a commercially available virtual reality game called Beat Saber. We did it in Unity from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our recreation, it not only read the beat maps from normal beat saber game but also includes many features like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tutorials for new players,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;practice trails to get players familiar with the game,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Auditory and visual feedback to reinforce the player’s behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multiple songs for participants to play&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And a scoring system to let the participants know how they are doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we developed a GUI that is only visible to the researcher and not visible to the participants in VR. The researcher can use the UI to manipulate the slice direction for our research study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game also will automatically save data about the player’s accuracy. This is much more efficient and less error-prone than manually enter data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use C# to create this game, GitHub for version control, and we deployed an agile method to conduct weekly sprints. And use kanban to track our progress across each sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers: Kalpa Anjur, Adrian Mester, Sebastian Yang, Matthew Komar, Adrian Ma, George Whitfield Jr, Suanna Moron&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentors: Cassondra Eng, Dr. Anna Fisher, Dr. Erik Thiessen&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="AR_VR" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><summary type="html">Promoting Cognitive Engagement and Physical Activity in Virtual Reality</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AnySync iOS App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AnySync iOS App" /><published>2021-03-12T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-12T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2021/spring/AnySync">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to do something with friends, but feared that your friends may turn you down? Even if your friends said yes, have you ever worried that they might have been pressured to say yes? This situation can happen when inviting friends to play video games or even in a couples’ sex life. Our app achieves true consent where both parties spontaneously say yes, but at different times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does it work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Create an activity and share it with your friends&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tap ”Sync” if you are in the mood&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If ONLY you tap, your friends would never know&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But if your friends are also in the mood, they will also tap “Sync” on their phones&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then both of you will be notified!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using our app, one party won’t feel discouraged if another party refuses. Because if one taps the “Sync” button, the other party won’t know it unless the other party also taps the button within the specified time-frame. You can even create as many syncs as you like for different purposes: “Friday Happy Hours”, ”Sex”, “Eat out tonight”, etc!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/anysync/id1556964175&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/anysync/id1556964175&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/anysync/appstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-notes&quot;&gt;Developers Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built with Swift, Google Firebase, and ReactJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed in CMU TartanHack 2021 under 40 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App Developed by Karl Xiao, Kevin Wang, and Sebastian Yang&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><summary type="html">Have you ever wanted to do something with friends, but feared that your friends may turn you down? Even if your friends said yes, have you ever worried that they might have been pressured to say yes? This situation can happen when inviting friends to play video games or even in a couples’ sex life. Our app achieves true consent where both parties spontaneously say yes, but at different times.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Legend of the White Snake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Legend of the White Snake" /><published>2020-12-20T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-20T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/WhiteSnake">&lt;p&gt;This is a retell of the Chinese traditional folklore &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legend_of_the_White_Snake&quot;&gt;The Legend of the White Snake&lt;/a&gt;. The game is developed for Tencent Institute of Games and is available for download at &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/%E7%99%BD%E8%9B%87-%E7%BA%B8%E4%BC%9E/id1535362205&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt; or by searching “白蛇·纸伞”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most challenging and exciting project I’ve worked on. I was the Product Manager/Programmer of the game and worked with 8 people across three different timezones to develop this game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led the team to go through 12 sprints in 3 months. We achieved weekly builds, hit 3 release milestones and conducted 5 rounds of user testings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/whitesnake/level1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/whitesnake/level1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Level 1&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, we did detailed documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://uvh2umbgwb.feishu.cn/docs/doccnYVvyg3TdKp4Whnhz6424id&quot;&gt;Game Design Doc (Chinese)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Links to user testing notes, and discussion notes are included in the last page of the design doc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Game_Development" /><summary type="html">This is a retell of the Chinese traditional folklore The Legend of the White Snake. The game is developed for Tencent Institute of Games and is available for download at Apple App Store or by searching “白蛇·纸伞”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What2Yum Mobile App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What2Yum Mobile App" /><published>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-15T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/fall/What2Yum">&lt;p&gt;Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What2Yum allows you to swipe yes or no on a set of restaurant cards. You can send a link to your group chat. After your friends finish swiping. We will combine your preferences with your friends to help you guys make the final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To download the full app &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/what2yum/appstore.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;developers-notes&quot;&gt;Developers Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is developed by Eileen Chen, Kevin Wang, and Sebastian Yang. We used SwiftUI for frontend and Google Firebase for backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we went through 7 iterations and we did detailed documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint1.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 1: Ideation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint2.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 2: User experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint3.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 3: API &amp;amp; Prototyping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint4.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 4: Version 1 of the app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint5.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 5: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/projects/what2yum/Sprint6.pdf&quot;&gt;Sprint 6: User testing of app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/what2yum/id1540868286&quot;&gt;Sprint 7: Ship!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><category term="Highlights" /><summary type="html">Ever take hours, days, or even weeks to decide what to eat with your friends or significant other? No more back and forth texting or indecisiveness — What2Yum can help you and your friends make a decision within minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Little Moochi Mobile Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Little Moochi Mobile Game" /><published>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/LittleMoochi">&lt;p&gt;LittleMoochi is an app to help kids develop healthy earting habits by raising their own AI-powered digital pets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply take a picture of your food to feed Moochi. The more balanced the food, the happier Moochi, and the family are. And… don’t forget the cool prizes for helping Moochi grow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the the app now at &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.LittleMoochi.LittleMoochi.Beta&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/littlemoochi/id1489071692&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt; or search “LittleMoochi”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/littlemoochi/id1489071692&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/LittleMoochi/screenshot.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Available on App Store&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;testing-environment&quot;&gt;Testing Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the testing environment for LittleMoochi’s marketing campaign mini game.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">LittleMoochi is an app to help kids develop healthy earting habits by raising their own AI-powered digital pets!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Game Jam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game Jam" /><published>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2020/spring/Pairs-of-Hearts">&lt;p&gt;Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received Best Diversity Theme Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by: Grace Liu, Jan Orlowski, Jess Cao, Joseph Perrino, Sebastian Yang. (alphabetical order)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.SebLab.PairsOfHearts&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><summary type="html">Developed in 2020 Global Game Jam in 30 hours</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This Website" /><published>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T19:40:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/spring/this-site">&lt;p&gt;This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#motivation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#first-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#second-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#two-point-five-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#third-iteration&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#future-plans&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are only interested in the technical portion, feel free to skip this part. : )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Websites are a great and interactive way to tell a story. When I’m reading a resume, I can only see a list of attributes as if I’m choosing a video game character by looking at his or her traits. But when I visit somebody’s website, I see a living human being with stories to tell. Hence, I want to present a more complete picture of myself to anyone who is interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I also want to have a place to record the interesting projects I’ve worked on. This idea came to me when during my high school graduation ceremony, a friend started talking about a research project we spent a few months working on in freshman year. I was confused because I don’t remember ever working on a research project with him. It wasn’t until that night did things starting to come back to me – it turned out we not only spent a few months on the project but also won a prize by doing a presentation on it but I totally forgot about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 10 or 20 years, it would be a shame if I forget about these interesting projects and the cool people I worked with. Even though I understand visitors are not going to read all the posts I wrote, these posts serve as a personal archive for me to remind myself of the people I worked with and the stuff we achieve together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s dive into the development of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-iteration&quot;&gt;First Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first iteration was developed in CMU67-250: The Information Systems Milieux. I developed an very simple website for a homework assignment.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/v18.3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The First Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first version is written in HTML, CSS, and JS. But as you can see, it looks very bad. If I hope to design an archive for my projects, I need it to look much better and more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Fun Fact: you can still visit this version of the site &lt;a href=&quot;/v18.3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;second-iteration&quot;&gt;Second Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design of the first iteration was unsalvageable. So I started redesigning the site from the ground up. I want the site to feel modern and interactive while being familiar to the user and can leave a strong impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about a week, every night after I finished my homework at around 10 pm, I would head to the Hunt Library. I spent one hour every night designing and developing this site. This version of the site looked pretty much the same as the one you see right now. The aesthetic and UI design you see right now are all designed and developed during that week. The only visual differences are that it had way fewer posts and there isn’t a &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;video game section&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/english.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Second Iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site was also fully responsive on mobile devices because I used the Bootstrap CSS framework and tested responsiveness every step during development. I then deployed the site on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In total, it took me about 10 hours across 7 days to finish and deploy this site. In hindsight, I was surprised because I had almost no web design experience back then, especially with code. But I guess when you are passionate about something, nothing can stop you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-point-five-iteration&quot;&gt;Two Point Five Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month after the second iteration, I translated the site to Chinese and bought a new domain name. I essentially deployed the same site to a new GitHub account, but the texts are all in Chinese.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/chinese.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The Chinese Site&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when I ran into some trouble: whenever I want to add a new post, I need to edit the HTML code and working with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;text&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; a lot. And add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; whenever I want a new line. This is super slow and frustrating, especially when I have a lot of text.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/html.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with HTML&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;third-iteration&quot;&gt;Third Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months after the Chinese site went online, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to rebuild the site from the ground up. Jekyll is a static site generator. This means after I set up the framework for all the posts, I can just write the content in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.markdownguide.org/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, which is very similar to writing text in a txt file.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/thissite/jekyll.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Working with Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also allows me to translate between Chinese and English sites seamlessly. Right now no matter which post you are reading, if you click the Chinese button, you will be taken to the Chinese translation of that site instead of the home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are developing a personal blog or portfolio site, I would highly recommend using Jekyll. It’s easy to learn, fun to use, and allows you to focus on the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-plans&quot;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this site as a hub for all my projects. I will continue to update the site with my latest projects. It may come a little late as I’m only available during summer or winter breaks. But I’m looking forward to adding more projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may also consider rebuilding the site again with &lt;a href=&quot;https://reactjs.org/&quot;&gt;React&lt;/a&gt;. This will allow me to make the site more interactive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I also added a new &lt;a href=&quot;/games.html&quot;&gt;Video Games&lt;/a&gt; section. But during my internship at Tencent Games and ByteDance Games, I played so many more games that I didn’t have time to update them all. I’m looking for a streamlined way to keep track of all the games I’ve played. I’m currently developing a full-stack website that will be my personal archive of games and books. The site should be able to export the database to a CSV file so that I can later do data analysis with R on the games I’ve played and books I’ve read.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="All" /><category term="Web_Design" /><category term="Software_Engineer" /><summary type="html">This website is entirely designed and developed by me, Sebastian Yang, with HTML, CSS, and JS. The site is populated with Jekyll and deployed on Github. It went through three iterations and it’s routinely updated. This post tells the story behind the website: what’s the purpose of this website, how it is developed, and my plans for it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boogieman VR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boogieman VR" /><published>2019-09-22T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/Boogieman-UnityVR">&lt;p&gt;This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we designed a VR rhythm dancing game. Our original idea was to use ML and OpenCV so that the player can dance freely. Then we realized that is not gamey enough. The final result is a beat-saber-like node-hitting dancing game — as you hit the nodes, you begin to boogie. We knew we succeed when during the final demo, not only the person in VR is dancing, but the entire class spontaneously started dancing to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this 6-week project, I was the programmer in the team. We will go through 6 iterations for the game, developing a prototype for each week and presenting a demo on every Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXyuNnvKIBo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-takeaways&quot;&gt;Main Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a highly intense 6-week project. I learned a lot about developing in VR. Here are some of my main takeaways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-never-seize-the-camera-in-vr&quot;&gt;1. Never Seize the Camera in VR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our game takes under the bed of a kid’s bedroom (the Bogeyman under the bed). In one of our iteration, we wanted to show the bedroom environment before going under the bed. So we added a “cut scene” where the camera will drop from above the bed to under the bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That…turned out to be a bad idea. Seizing the camera meant the play lost control of his or her own head. It’s disorienting and dizzy. Not to mention the drop in height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-use-visual-cues-to-direct-the-players-view&quot;&gt;2. Use Visual Cues to Direct the Player’s view&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we cannot seize the camera and add cut scenes, this means a player can have total control over the camera movement. This is also where VR stands out from flat-screen media: VR invites the player to discover the environment in a self-paced way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That also means the player may miss key animations and moments in the game. For example, in our early iterations, the dance floor is a square. We noticed many players missed the Boogieman entrance animation completely and are not sure where they should face. We later change the dance floor to a long strip to guide the player to look at the Boogieman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-if-it-seems-interactive-it-needs-to-be&quot;&gt;3. If it seems interactive, it needs to be&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, I saw many players feeling disappointed when they try to pick the toys in the environment up and failed. It made our game less immersive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic of VR is the feeling of presence in a virtual world. Hence, users will naturally apply the rules of the real world to the virtual world. If something looks like it can be picked up, pressed, or thrown, it better should be or else it will ruin the immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t have time to implement this in our 6-week production schedule but it’s a good takeaway to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game is made by (in alphabetical order): Ann Maria, Connie Chau, Kalpa Anjur, Lisa Lo, Carter Williams, and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for making this amazing dancing game a reality!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><category term="Highlights" /><category term="AR_VR" /><summary type="html">This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PuttPlot VR</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PuttPlot VR" /><published>2019-09-21T20:40:23-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-21T20:40:23-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/fall/PuttPlot-UnityVR">&lt;p&gt;Published on Oct 29, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a team project for CMU 53-451: Research Issues in Game Development: Designing for XR. This is a game-design/research class taught by Professor Tom Corbett where we work in teams to design video games in VR/AR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we designed a golf-dating-sim called PuttPlot. Essentially, it is a Japanese-style dating sim but you choose your response by golfing the ball to the corresponding holes. This is both challenging and fun in that we need to simulate the 3D golfing gestures and physics in VR but at the same time tell an interesting story through 2D animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this 6-week project, I was the producer/programmer in the team. We will go through 6 iterations for the game, developing a prototype for each week and presenting a demo on every Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;no_toc&quot; id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-1---brain-storming&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-1---brain-storming&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Brain Storming&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-2---pre-production&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-2---pre-production&quot;&gt;Week 2 - Pre-Production&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-1&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming-1&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#feedback-for-this-week&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-feedback-for-this-week&quot;&gt;Feedback for this week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-3---a-rough-week-&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-3---a-rough-week-&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Rough Week :(&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-2&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot;&gt;Programming - A Ramp is Built&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-4---play-testing&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-4---play-testing&quot;&gt;Week 4 - Play-Testing&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing---a-small-bug&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing---a-small-bug&quot;&gt;Producing - A “Small” Bug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-cont&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-cont&quot;&gt;Producing (CONT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Is on Fire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot;&gt;Week 5 - Things Are Finally Coming Together&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-3&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-3&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp is Never On&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned-1&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned-1&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#week-6---release&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-week-6---release&quot;&gt;Week 6 - Release&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#producing-4&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-producing-4&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Broke, Again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lesson-learned-2&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lesson-learned-2&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#credits&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-1---brain-storming&quot;&gt;Week 1 - Brain Storming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot of freedom in our project. The only requirement was that it needed to be a playable VR game inspired by any picnic game. And, of course, it needed to be developed within 6-week by a team of 5-6 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We formed our team on Friday, Aug 30th. On the next day, we had our first meeting. In the meeting, we spend about 4 hours talking about game ideas. Our discussion ranged from a technical-challenged beat-saber-style &lt;em&gt;Hall Ball&lt;/em&gt; to an Americano dark-humor game called &lt;em&gt;Catch With Dad&lt;/em&gt;. The game idea I proposed was an environmental-educational sandbox game called &lt;em&gt;Tree&lt;/em&gt; where you grow and destroy tress to impact global temperature. Sadly, it is a bit out of scope for a 6-week project so we didn’t end up running it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several rounds of voting, we ended up with the idea of a dating simulation golf game: &lt;em&gt;PuttPlot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we decided the game idea, we need to present a playable demo that following Friday. We cooperated by assigning tasks to each individual in the team. These were tasks like demo-board design, 2D arts and hitting mechanics. All individual task would be due by Wednesday night. And we would use Thursday night to integrate all the individual parts into a full game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our first demo, we just used rigid-body on the ball and added a collider on the golf club. We would add a force on the ball to the direction of the club whenever the ball was hit. So Unity physics will handle the collision and how golf ball would fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did pretty well for our first week. Our demo is working and the class seems to like it. We also received a lot of constructive feedback.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week1.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Concept Art for the game&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-2---pre-production&quot;&gt;Week 2 - Pre-Production&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get things going, we did a lot of pre-production work this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-1&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we decided on the three pillars of the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laughter: the game should be very very funny / subverted expectations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engaging stories: player’s decisions matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board configuration connect to dialogue options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our game mainly consisted of two parts: a golfing mechanics and an intriguing story. So for the second week, our writer Gus worked on the story and ended up with a bunch of index card full of funny stories he wrote. Our artiest Angelina worked on more concepts and character art. Our programmer Carter and Ann worked on driving golf. And I worked on the board design and producing work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still used the integrate-on-Thursday-present-on-Friday approach. Since a lot of the work we did is preproduction, the final demo we presented on Friday for this week isn’t that much different from the previous week.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-story.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-story.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Draft story tree for the game&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-1&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week we try to mimic how golf ball in the real world works. In real life, the golf ball will not fly away immediately after contact with the club, but will instead be lifted a bit by the club and the fly away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we try to do that in the game by adding the ball to be a child object of the club immediately after contact so that it would stick to the club. After the ball move up to the direction of the swing for a few milliseconds, we will release the ball and adding a force to make it fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is good but the final result wasn’t as successful as we would want it to be. The ball still moves too fast and didn’t land on the location you would expect it to land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback-for-this-week&quot;&gt;Feedback for this week&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same as last week, we received a lot of feedback after our demo on Friday and we boiled down to four points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ball was too fast/not visible enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text looked bad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board UI needed work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Driving doesn’t feel good. Need a RAMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we forget to record gameplay video in the first two iterations so you won’t be able to see them.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-game.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week2-game.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The second iteration&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-3---a-rough-week-&quot;&gt;Week 3 - A Rough Week :(&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our third iteration of the game, things started to get a bit difficult. We had the Technical Opportunities Conference this week, which is the biggest career fair on CMU each year. Many teammates spent all their free time on Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday in that event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-2&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This essentially meant our Wednesday checkpoint was not met. So we ended up trying to scramble everything together at the last minute. Carter, Gus and I stayed at Hunt Library basement until after midnight. Even after that, the version we submitted was still very buggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed several levels(boards) for the game. But because we failed to get the dialogue transition working in time. We never got a chance to transit to the new levels. Therefore, our demo on Friday was not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---a-ramp-is-built&quot;&gt;Programming - A Ramp is Built&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good thing was we got a working ramp. One of the feedback that we received was that just driving the ball to the board did’t feel good. We solved this by adding an acceleration ramp. In this case, the player only needs to putt the ball to the ramp and ball will fly up to the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, we will do better next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Sep 28, 2019.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week3-ramp.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week3-ramp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;The ramp&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-4---play-testing&quot;&gt;Week 4 - Play-Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are officially passing the halfway point of our project but we still haven’t got the core game loop ready. So there is only one goal this week: nail down the game loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing---a-small-bug&quot;&gt;Producing - A “Small” Bug&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning from last week’s experience, we tried to add more checkpoints and iterations throughout the week. Instead of only integrating on Thursday night, we integrated and play-test on Tuesday night and integrated again on Wednesday and Thursday nights. This meant we could at least iterate two times in one week: one for play-testing on Tuesday and one for the demo on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, we were fixing bugs while inviting people to play-test. Near the end of the play-test session, we fixed all the bugs that are left from last week, especially a bug that will prevent the dialogue from moving to the next board and options.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-environment.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-environment.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Week4 the environment behind the player&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we found a smaller bug. Instead of creating a new ball and destroy old ones, we cycled through golf balls. This meant there are only 10 golf balls in total in the game. We created these ball at the beginning of the game and when you hit the ball with index 9, the ball with index 0 will come back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since we only changed its transform.location, there were still forces on the ball if the player went through all the balls very quickly. Since we were play-testing, there was no time to rewrite the script, we just changed the number of balls from 10 to 100000000 in the editor, thinking there is no way a player could go through 100000000 balls that quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the play button, without thinking twice. But apparently, initializing 100000000 game objects in a for-loop at the beginning of the game is a bad idea …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unity stopped responding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were thinking: “Cool, I’ll just have to reopen Unity and change the number back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we forgot to save the scene before entering that huge number…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So all the modifications we made that night in the scene was gone…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-cont&quot;&gt;Producing (CONT)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All was not lost. We integrated again on Wednesday to revert all the changes we made on Tuesday. And we also integrated on Thursday to add more features like background, voice and more dialogue. At around 11:20 pm on Thursday, when we tried to integrate all the dialogue scriptable objects and voice to our main game, the game broke again because my teammates were using the older version of the event system (the one from last week) and we changed the system since then…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent 10-20 mins trying to fix this issue. This meant we only have 20 mins left to integrate. We have to make a hard choice, either we could put all the dialogue in so the player can play a full game without voice acting, or we could put the dialogue and voice acting for the first scene so the player can experience a shorter but complete game loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the producer, it was a hard choice for me to make. Because both sides have spent a lot of time tonight working and both would like their stuff in the game. But I decided to go with the latter because a short snapshot of our game can provide people a better understanding of the game and what the game would look like once it is finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-is-on-fire&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Is on Fire&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We moved the golf ball’s location around and didn’t have time to recalibrate the boosting ramp. So in our demo on Friday, when our TA Adrian tested the game, the ramp boosted too much and he overshot the ball a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something can go wrong, it will go wrong… So save files periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Oct 5, 2019.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-player-view.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week4-player-view.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Week4 Player's View&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-5---things-are-finally-coming-together&quot;&gt;Week 5 - Things Are Finally Coming Together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With two weeks to go, we finally nailed down our core game loop. This week we got all the major elements integrated: story, putting, environment and some voice acting in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-3&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the organizational changes, we made last week worked, we again play-tested our game on Tuesday night and integrate it on Wednesday and Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because our game is dialogue-focused, once we got the dialogue system set up the game would work decently. So this week we saw all the previous debugging and coding efforts finally paid off (special thanks to our lead programmer Carter). We also added a chat history on the sides of the player, so that the player can see the previous chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-is-never-on&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp is Never On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that in week 3 we added a ramp？And in week 4 the ramp makes the player overshot a lot? This was actually kind of wired because in week 3 the ramp would not cause as much overshooting as it did in week 4. So this week we try to solve that problem by recalibrating the ramp and the ball’s landing location on the board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the entire evening with a headset on in our VR game while Carter tweaked parameters for the ramp. Each time he tweaked something, I would the ramp and see where the ball lands. And each time we do that, we would convince ourselves that we are almost there, just a few more tweaks to go.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
      &lt;a href=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week5-recalibrate.gif&quot; title=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&quot; /images/projects/PuttPlot/week5-recalibrate.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;w-100&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Recalibrating the Ramp&lt;/p&gt;
    


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- source from https://superdevresources.com/image-caption-jekyll/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, we were a bit frustrated because no matter how we tweak the parameters, the ramp would always overshoot. Wait a minute, no matter how we change the parameters … the outcome would not change… it could only be … but that’s impossible …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, the ramp’s collider was never turned on. The collider that was supposed to detect and boost the ball, the collider that we thought we were changing was never on. We must have turned it off during some testing and forgot to turn it back on. Because it was off, it had absolutely no effects in the game. And we just spent about an hour trying to “fix” it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we turn the collider on, everything worked decently. In our demo on Friday, our guest, a naive play-tester, seemed impressed by our game, especially how easy the putting feels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned-1&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains, no matter how improbable, must be the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written on Oct 11, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;week-6---release&quot;&gt;Week 6 - Release&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is our final week to work on the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;producing-4&quot;&gt;Producing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After play-testing the game on Tuesday, we listed 10-12 additional features and improvements we wanted to add to the game. Our biggest challenge this week was getting all the voice and dialogue lines in. As I have said before, once we got the main dialogue system working, it would just be a matter of click and drag all the files in. But since we were trying to create a funny dating simulator, we have a long story (consisted of 7 short stories with branches). It took us a long time to put all the dialogue lines and its’ corresponding voice acting in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 9:30 pm on Thursday, we managed to get the whole game working (without voice acting). I play-tested the entire game while our writer Gus was putting voices into the scriptable objects for each dialogue. Surprisingly, because we had too many jokes and stories, it took me a good 20-30 minutes to finish the entire game. The version we had right now would be our last-known-good in case things went south.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished adding all the voices acting in at around 10:50 - 11:00 pm, about one hour before the deadline. Then, things went south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming---the-ramp-broke-again&quot;&gt;Programming - The Ramp Broke, Again&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programming section of this article was created to talk about the technical challenges we faced during the game development. But I just realized almost all of them are actually about the ramp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 11:00 pm, one hour before the deadline, we decided to recalibrate the ramp (again). This was because we added a tutorial to this game. The tutorial would ask the player to shoot the far left and far right of the board, so that players would know how to control the putting. But, currently, shooting to the side would cause a bug on the ramp, making the golf ball never land on the board. We never notice this problem last week because we did not add the tutorial until this week. So with one hour to go, we started debugging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carter and I started our classic duel: He would tweak different parameters on the ramp and I would be in the headset hitting the golf ball and giving him feedback. But we encountered the same problem: no matter how we tweak the parameters, the boosting effect would not be activated for all the balls landing on the far sides of the ramp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked the collider, yes, it was on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 11:45 pm, the atmosphere was tense. On the one hand, hitting the ball up through the ramp was our core game mechanics, we have an obligation to make it work. On the other hand, we had no idea whether we could solve this bug or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 11:50 pm, we found the bug. It was one line of code in the ramp’s script that narrowed the range of checking collision. After we simply commented it out, things worked beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, we presented our game to the whole class. Even though we still had some problems with the putting, the play-test went well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I made a mistake here. I should have built the game after we added all the voice acting and before we started debugging the ramp. This is because our last-know-good was the version built around 9:30 pm. It did not have all the voice acting in. Had the debugging effort failed, and the game fails to compile before midnight, all the effort of recording the voice acting and adding it to the game would be lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lesson-learned-2&quot;&gt;Lesson Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last-Known-Good is your friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nhujQxwyqC4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first time working on a game as producer. It is really a learning experience for me. I am very grateful to have a supportive team. I’d really like to give a shout-out to our programmer Carter Williams, our writer Gus Saalfeld and our artiest Angelina Shi. This game would not be possible without their’s and all our teammates contribution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Product_Project_Management" /><category term="Game_Development" /><category term="All" /><category term="AR_VR" /><summary type="html">Published on Oct 29, 2019.</summary></entry></feed>